All living beings value your life.   A
Hết thảy chúng sanh đều quý bạn sống.
Buddha is a Buddha who has attained enlightenment.  All sentient beings
Phật là Phật đã thành. Tất cả chúng sanh
are Buddhas in the future.  Regarding the letter, it conveys a message of
là Phật sẽ thành. Về sắc gửi thông điệm
peace.
hòa bình.
Everyone born into this world longs to be
Ai sinh ra trên đời cũng mong được yêu
loved.  Everyone born into this world desires
thương. Ai sinh ra trên đời cũng muốn
peace.
được bình yên.
Oh, storms, tempests, raging fires,
Nào bão tô phong ba lửa cháy cùng lú
forgetting to sing, and epidemics—oh, those
quên hẳn hát và dịch bệnh
eyes filled with hopelessness and
ôi đôi mắt trong vô
sorrow. Everyone born into this world longs to
thương ai sinh ra trên đời cũng mong
be loved; everyone born into this world
được yêu thương ai sinh ra trên đờ
desires peace.   Let us
cũng muốn được bình yên.
not create more
Chớ chớ tạo thêm chiến
wars, let us put an end to conflict, let us
tranh hãy hãy châm dứt chiên
cooperate and live in harmony for peace and
trời hợp tác cùng hòa hợp khắp toàn cầu
happiness throughout the world.
an vui.
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Let there be more
Đớ cho tạo thêm chiến
wars, or let there be an end to
trời hay châm dứt chiên
wars, let there be unity and
trời đoàn kết và bao
tolerance for world peace.
dung cho thế giới hòa bình.
Buddha Shakyamuni's
Phật Thích Ca Mâu
compassion extended to
Ni sinh lòng từ
all beings, reaching far and wide, like the flower of
bi trài khắp muôn loài về xa người thông
compassion.
điệm hoa bi.
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Oh
Oh
Everyone born into this world longs to be
Ai sinh ra trên đời cũng mong được yêu
loved.  Everyone born into this world desires
thương. Ai sinh ra trên đời cũng muốn
peace.
được bình yên.
Oh, storms, tempests, raging fires, madness,
Nào bão tô phong ba lửa cháy cùng lú
kidney stones, singing, and disease! Oh, those
quết thận hát và dịch bệnh
eyes filled with hopelessness and
ôi đôi mắt trong vô
sorrow! Everyone born into this world longs to
thương ai sinh ra trên đời cũng mong
be loved, everyone born into this world
được yêu thương ai sinh ra trên đờ
desires peace.   Do not
cũng muốn được bình yên.
thank the
Chớ chớ tạ thân chiên
heavenly sheep.  Let us put an end to the
trời. Hãy hay chấm dứt chiên
war and instead cooperate and live in harmony for peace and happiness across the globe
trời hợp tác cùng hòa hợp khắp toàn cầu
.
an vui.
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
Let there be more
Đớ cho tạo thêm chiến
wars, or let there be an end to
trời hay châm dứt chiên
wars, let there be unity and
trời đoàn kết và bao
tolerance for world peace.
dung cho thế giới hòa bình.
Buddha Shakyamuni, with boundless compassion, extended his loving-kindness to
Phật Thích Ca Mâu
all beings, his smile spreading far and wide like a
bi trài khắp muôn loài về xa cười thông
field of blooming flowers.
điền hoa bi.
The song goes far
Đề sang về
away, praying for world
xa cầu thế giới hòa
peace, going far away, praying to end the war, going far away, the wise
bình về sang về sang nguyện châm dứt
man,
xa người thông điên hòa
peace, going far away, the wise man,
bình về sang về sang người thông điền
peace, going far away, the
hòa
wise man,
về xa người thông điện hòa
peace, going far away, the wise man,
bình về sang về sang người thông
peace
điền hoa bình
[music]
[âm nhạc]
He.
He.
Oh
Oh